[Music]
Today we're going to look at high
protein keto vanilla cookies and cream.
I get asked to do high protein and keto
recipes a lot. Um I don't know why I do
don't do more. So here we go. Today
we're going to do a cookies and cream.
Um
hold on.
I picked these up. Yeah, these are high
protein ultra low sugar cookies. This is
going to be an inch creamy because my
muzo has died. The motor has given up
and I'm trying to find someone to fix it
before I attempt to fix it myself. So,
for for a little bit, we're going to do
ninja creamy recipes. So, let's just get
on and do this protein one. What are we
going to need for this high protein, no
added sugar keto cookies and cream? You
are going to need 290 g of high protein
milk. I'm using Nutrell 2% which is
higher protein than Fairlife milk if
you're interested. 290 gram of whipping
cream, 33 to 36% fat cream, 80 gram of
xylitol, 85 grams of vanilla protein
powder, and 8 g of vanilla extract. The
vanilla extract, whether you use
alcohol- based or glycerin based, it
will do the same thing. That is to help
adjust the freezing point and to boost
that vanilla flavor. xylitol because
it's much safer to use than arythritol.
There's a whole thing with ariththrtol.
People think I hate it. I actually do
hate it. It recristallizes regardless of
how much you use. It will recristallize.
It's just how much time it takes to
recristallize. Um so yeah, I I don't
really like arythrtol. You can use it in
low numbers, but if you do, you need to
stabilize it. But I'll talk about that
in maybe the next video. So, let's just
get everything weighed out and let's get
going. So, let's start with our milk.
This came from Safeway, I think. But,
um, this has 7.2%
by weight protein. Fair Life has 5.2%
by weight protein. So, it's considerably
higher. So, 290
g. This is gonna make one Ninja Creamy
Deluxe sized batch. So, if you want
more, then adjust the recipe to suit.
290 g of that. 290 g of our cream. 80 g
of xylitol. Yes, you can use alulos. Um,
you'll need to use a little bit more
because it doesn't have quite a strong
effect on the freezing point.
And we're going to put those two after
we heat this up. We're not going to heat
this up super high. We're just going to
warm this on the hob just for 5 minutes
just to get that xylitol dissolved. It
will dissolve on its own if you stir it
for long enough. So, but I'm just going
to hurry the process along. While we're
waiting for that, let's get our protein.
This is pure protein
vanilla, 25 g per serving. Um, you have
to just be careful the amount of sugar
that's added into your protein powder.
Some are loaded with sugar, some aren't.
Get rid of that. Got a million of those.
Don't need any more. 85 g. We need this.
I mean, it's barely warm, but we don't
want to get this too hot. If you if you
cook protein powder, it can go a bit
weird. So we are now so we're going to
add in our protein powder
and get that combined. The biggest
problem with making protein ice cream in
a normal churn machine is the viscosity.
it it's really it can go really really
thick and that is because in your
protein powders you got things like um
maltodextrin cellulose gum zantham gum
you know you got stabilizers plus you've
just got an exceedingly high amount of
solids going into that base so the
viscosity will get too high so you
that's why for a really good protein ice
cream in a churn machine you have to
bring that protein down in a ninja
creamy and that that type of machine,
you don't have that issues because you
you you're not churning it. You're
you're just decimating the whole thing.
So, you're not you don't have to worry
about inclusion of air, which you just
wouldn't be able to do. But now that
we've got our protein completely mixed
in, in goes our vanilla extract. And
that is just going to bring
a more natural vanilla flavor to this
rather than the artificial vanilla that
all of this is flavored with. Some
actually are flavored with real vanilla,
but you're paying a lot for that. If you
want to increase the vanilla, true
vanilla flavor, use vanilla bean powder,
which is just ground vanilla beans. It
won't affect the freezing point, won't
adjust the temperature. You can just
increase the vanilla flavor. So, with
that in mind, there's that.
Into our Ninja Creamy tub.
So, there that goes. In the freezer it
goes. As this hasn't been heated, it
won't take as long to freeze hard. So,
let's see how long. It's 10 9 in the
morning. Let's see how long this takes
to freeze. Use whatever vanilla protein
powder you have. As long as your protein
powder isn't full of sugar or sugar
alcohols that will adjust your freezing
point, you'll be fine. But to be fair, I
I don't think many are like that these
days. Anyway, see you in a bit. This is
the next day. I didn't get around to
doing it yesterday, but
looks good. It's dense.
Let's
get this in.
Get it spun.
Should I plug it in?
All
[Applause]
right, we got our crushed cookies. Uh,
did those not crushed a cut? Let's
get that out there.
Going to do the classic, you know, make
a make a divot in the middle. Right.
Back in.
Uh, what am I going to do? mix in.
All right.
[Music]
There we go. Super nice scoop.
There we go. Like I said, these cookies
are keto friendly cookies. So, there's
four grams of protein
per serving. So, what's that? Two
cookies. 24 g um 6 g of fat, 2 g of
sugar, 4 g of alulose, chocolate mint.
The ice cream scooped really nicely.
It's dense,
super nice
vanilla flavor of the protein powder
comes flooding through, but right at the
end, you get that actual natural flavor
from the vanilla extract coming through
as well, which is kind of what you want.
You want that vanilla to just make that
vanilla flavor a bit more
manageable. And you know what, the
chocolate and mint cookies goes really
well. You got three different flavors
going on here. It's uh it's really nice.
So, there we go. High protein keto
cookies and cream, vanilla flavored ice
cream with chocolate mint cookies, just
any cookies you like really. But I
wanted to keep the cookies on point with
the whole keto thing. We've got Ninja
Cream Recipes coming up for the next few
weeks at least because my Muso is busted
and I'm not paying hundreds of dollars
to ship it to the other side of the
country to get it repaired. So, I'm
going to look at repairing it myself.
But next week, it's full, so pumpkin
spice gelato in the Ninja Creamy. Thanks
very much for watching. Don't forget to
like and subscribe, and I'll see you
next week.
[Music]